# **Spencer Creer**

4242 W. Old Orchard Ln. Cedar Hills, UT 84062 (385) 292-6306

spencercreer@gmail.com https://github.com/spencercreer https://spencercreer.github.io/portfolio/

#### **Overview**

Full-stack web developer with experience in JavaScript, jQuery, Express, and React. Mechanical Engineer with a passion for product development. Top performing business leader and sales manager focused on company growth and increased revenue. Goal oriented leader with excellent communication and team working skills.

# **Professional Experience**

Moxtek. Inc.

*July 2019 to current* 

#### Sales Engineer II

- Manage the European sales of tube and detector products for the x-ray spectrometry division
- Maintain and improve the company website using WordPress
- Quote new opportunities and inquiries.
- Wrote an Excel VBA Macro to efficiently track consignment inventory cutting time by two-thirds

Advanced Composites, Inc.

January 2019 to July 2019

# **Technical Sales Specialist**

- Managed sales of composite products in the aerospace, defense, and medical industries
- Generated new business opportunities through customer relations, trade shows, and other sales activities
- Developed a more efficient shipping and packaging solution cutting costs by about \$100,000 yearly
- Worked with engineers to develop a solution to achieve more accurate and precise tolerances

New Star Communications Int. Inc., American Fork, UT

*May 2014 to January 2019* 

# Sales Manager

- Managed the Cleveland, Ohio office of twenty-seven sales representatives responsible for 1,535 new account activations equaling 1.2 million dollars of revenue growth in 2017
- Responsible for 1,152 personal accounts over four years
- Top first-year sales representative with a total of 232 personal accounts in 2014
- Amongst the top five sales representatives in production and quality four years consecutively

New Star Communications Int. Inc., American Fork, UT

November 2011 to May 2014

# **Call Center Manager**

#### **Education**

Brigham Young University

January 2012 to December 2018

Mechanical Engineering Bachelors of Science Global Business and Literacy Minor & German Minor University of Utah

November 2020 to May 2021

### **Full-Stack Web Development Diploma**

# **Skills and Accomplishments**

- Proficient in HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, React, and Python
- Skilled in the manufacturing processes of composite materials including layup, resin infusion, filament winding, and curing
- Passed the NCEES Fundamentals of Engineering (FE) exam
- Familiar with MIL and AS9100 quality standards
- Experience with NX, Solidworks, C++, Matlab, ANSYS, and LabView.
- Participant on the L3 Technologies Capstone team at Brigham Young University
- Winner of the Fall 2016 Brigham Young University mechatronics robotics competition
- Chinese visa
- Volunteer service missionary from November 2009 to November 2011 for the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints in Munich, Germany
- Proficient in German language, reading, writing, and speaking

### References

Nathaniel Olsen VP of Sales New Star Communications Int. Inc. (801) 318-7250 olsen1414@gmail.com Jerry Cooney VP of Sales and Marketing Advanced Composites, Inc. (801) 467-1204 cooney.jerry@gmail.com

Doug Fillmore VP, Human Resources & Administration Moxtek, Inc. (801) 376-9915